<sect2 id="diskt">
<title>The Disk Targets Tab</title>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject role="html">
<imagedata fileref="images/diskt.jpg" format="JPG" align="center"/>
</imageobject>
<imageobject role="fo">
<imagedata fileref="images/diskt.jpg" format="JPG" align="center"/>
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
<para>
The Disk Targets tab lets you see and control the disks used by the disk 
worker(s) currently selected in the Topology panel. You can control which 
disks are used, how much of each disk is used, the maximum number of 
outstanding I/Os per disk for each worker, and how frequently the disks 
are opened and closed.
</para><para>
By Clicking, Shift-click, and Control-click you can select any number of 
drives to be used by the selected worker(s) during the test.
</para><para>
Physical drives are displayed with a blue disk icon and the name 
<emphasis>PHYSICALDRIVE:n</emphasis> (only if they contain nothing but 
free space).
</para><para>
Logical drives are displayed with a yellow disk icon and a drive letter 
and optional name (only if they are writable). Logical drives are accessed 
by writing to a file called \iobw.tst. If this file does not exist, the 
drive's icon has a red slash through it. At the start of the test the file
will be created and grown until the disk is full.
</para><para>
Running with physical drives is recommended.
</para><para>
If a disk worker is selected in the Topology panel, that worker's current 
configuration is displayed in the Disk Targets tab; any changes you make 
affect only that worker. 
</para><para>
If a manager or <emphasis>All Managers</emphasis> is selected, the disk 
workers' common configuration is displayed: controls (other than Target 
assignments) for which all workers have the same setting show that 
setting, while controls for which not all workers have the same setting 
are blank. <emphasis role="bold">Any changes you make in the Disk Targets 
tab are  applied to all of the selected manager or managers' 
workers.</emphasis>
</para><para>
If a network worker is selected in the Topology panel, the Disk Targets 
tab is disabled. Clicking on a network worker while the Disk Targets tab 
is displayed automatically switches to the Network Targets tab. The same 
applies to a manager that has no disk workers, or <emphasis>All 
Managers</emphasis> if no manager has any disk workers.
</para>

&targets;


</sect2>

