<sect1 id="intro">
<title>Introduction</title>
<para>
Iometer is an I/O subsystem measurement and characterization tool for
single and clustered systems. Iometer is pronounced "eye-OM-i-ter," to
rhyme with "thermometer." Iometer does for a computer's I/O subsystem what
a dynamometer does for an engine: it measures performance under a
controlled load. Iometer was formerly known as "Galileo."
</para><para>
Iometer is both a workload generator (that is, it performs I/O operations
in order to stress the system) and a measurement tool (that is, it
examines and records the performance of its I/O operations and their
impact on the system). It can be configured to emulate the disk or
network I/O load of any program or benchmark, or can be used to generate
entirely synthetic I/O loads. It can generate and measure loads on single 
or multiple (networked) systems.
</para><para>
Iometer can be used for measurement and characterization of:
</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>
Performance of disk and network controllers.
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Bandwidth and latency capabilities of buses.
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Network throughput to attached drives.
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Shared bus performance.
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
System-level hard drive performance.
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
System-level network performance.
</para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>
Iometer consists of two programs, Iometer and Dynamo.
</para><para>
<emphasis>Iometer</emphasis> is the controlling program. Using Iometer's
graphical user interface, you configure the workload, set operating
parameters, and start and stop tests. Iometer tells Dynamo what to do,
collects the resulting data, and summarizes the results in output files.
Only one copy of Iometer should be running at a time; it is typically run
on the server machine.
</para><para>
<emphasis>Dynamo</emphasis> is the workload generator. It has no user
interface. At Iometer's command, Dynamo performs I/O operations and
records performance information, then returns the data to Iometer. There
can be more than one copy of Dynamo running at a time; typically one copy
runs on the server machine and one additional copy runs on each client
machine. Dynamo is multithreaded; each copy can simulate the workload of
multiple client programs. Each running copy of Dynamo is called a
manager; each thread within a copy of Dynamo is called a worker.
</para>
<sect2 id="new">
<title>What's new?</title>
<para>
The current version of Iometer is 2003.12.16. Here are some of the more
significant changes since the last version (2003.05.10):
</para><para>
New features:
</para><para>
For a complete list of all enhancements and bug fixes since the previous
version, please see the file "CHANGELOG".
</para><para>
NOTE
</para><para>
It is important to keep in mind, that resuls might not be comparable
between two different Iometer versions. For example if there was an error
in the old version you might see this effect.
</para></sect2>
<sect2 id="copyright">
<title>Copyright and License</title>
<para>
This document, <emphasis>Iometer User's Guide</emphasis>, is copyrighted 
&copy; by <emphasis>The Iometer Project Group</emphasis>, 
Permission is granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document 
under the terms of the GNU Free Document License, Version 1.1 or any later 
version published by the Free Software Foundation; with no Back-Cover 
texts. A copy of the license is available at <ulink 
url="http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/fdl.html">
http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/fdl.html</ulink>
</para>
<para>
The program(s), <emphasis>Iometer</emphasis> and 
<emphasis>Dynamo</emphasis> are release under the <emphasis>Intel Open 
Software License</emphasis> which is displayed the first time you run 
iometer. A copy of the license is available at <ulink 
url="http://www.iometer.org/doc/licenses/iosl.txt">www.iometer.org</ulink> 
website.
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="disclaimer">
<title>Disclaimer</title>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>
No liability for the contents of this document can be accepted.
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Iometer is provided <emphasis>"as-is"</emphasis>, without warranty or
guarantee of any kind.
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Intel does not endorse, support, or guarantee Iometer performance results.
</para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="contribute">
<title>Credits / Contributors</title>
<para>
Put info here
</para>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="feedback">
<title>Feedback</title>
<para>
Iometer is provided <emphasis>"as-is"</emphasis>, but we are interested in
input from you. If you have a problem while running Iometer our found a
bug you should consult the Know Issues page first at <ulink
url="http://www.iometer.org/doc/issues.html">
http://www.iometer.org/doc/issues.html</ulink>
</para><para>
There you will find workarounds for this known issues. If you have a new
issue you might join the iometer-user mailing list (see <ulink
url="http://lists.sourceforge.net/lists/listinfo/iometer-user">
http://lists.sourceforge.net/lists/listinfo/iometer-user</ulink>) and ask
the
community for help. If it is a real bug, then please provide a patch or
go ahead and file the bug at <ulink
url="http://sourceforge.net/projects/iometer">
http://sourceforge.net/projects/iometer</ulink>
</para><para>
We cannot promise to fix any bugs or provide any requested features, but
we try to read and respond to all our mail. Be sure to include all
information necessary to reproduce the problem, including the version
number of Iometer. If you aren't using the current version, you will be
asked to reproduce the problem using the current version before any
action is taken on the bug report.
</para></sect2>
 </sect1> 

