<sect2 id="topology">
<title>The Topology Panel</title>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject role="html">
<imagedata fileref="images/topo.jpg" format="JPG" align="left"/>
</imageobject>
<imageobject role="fo">
<imagedata fileref="images/topo.jpg" format="JPG" align="left"/>
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
<para>
The Topology panel displays a hierarchical list of the managers (copies of 
Dynamo) and workers (threads within each copy of Dynamo) currently active. 
This panel is a hierarchical list like the one used in Windows Explorer. 
</para><para>
To display or hide a manager's workers, double-click on the manager's 
name, or click the plus or minus sign to the left of the manager's
name.
</para><para>
The icons that appear in the Topology panel are as follows:
</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><inlinemediaobject>
<imageobject role="html">
<imagedata fileref="images/topo1.jpg" format="JPG" align="left"/>
</imageobject>
<imageobject role="fo">
<imagedata fileref="images/topo1.jpg" format="JPG" align="left"/>
</imageobject>
</inlinemediaobject>
All managers connected to this copy of Iometer.
</para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><inlinemediaobject>
<imageobject role="html">
<imagedata fileref="images/topo2.jpg" format="JPG" align="left"/>
</imageobject>
<imageobject role="fo">
<imagedata fileref="images/topo2.jpg" format="JPG" align="left"/>
</imageobject>
</inlinemediaobject>
A manager.
</para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><inlinemediaobject>
<imageobject role="html">
<imagedata fileref="images/topo3.jpg" format="JPG" align="left"/>
</imageobject>
<imageobject role="fo">
<imagedata fileref="images/topo3.jpg" format="JPG" align="left"/>
</imageobject>
</inlinemediaobject>
A disk worker.
</para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><inlinemediaobject>
<imageobject role="html">
<imagedata fileref="images/topo4.jpg" format="JPG" align="left"/>
</imageobject>
<imageobject role="fo">
<imagedata fileref="images/topo4.jpg" format="JPG" align="left"/>
</imageobject>
</inlinemediaobject>
A network server.
</para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><inlinemediaobject>
<imageobject role="html">
<imagedata fileref="images/topo5.jpg" format="JPG" align="left"/>
</imageobject>
<imageobject role="fo">
<imagedata fileref="images/topo5.jpg" format="JPG" align="left"/>
</imageobject>
</inlinemediaobject>
A network client (created automatically when you select a
target for a network server). Its name reflects the name of its
corresponding network server.
</para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>
Network servers and network clients are both referred to as network 
workers.
</para><para>
Iometer starts a single manager, on the same machine as Iometer, when it 
starts up.
</para><para>
By clicking on a worker, manager, or All Managers you are able to see and 
change its settings in the Disk Targets, Network Targets, and Access 
Specifications tabs.
</para><para>
If you click on a worker, targets (disks or network interfaces) selected 
in the Disk Targets or Network Targets tab are used by that worker. The 
other controls in the Disk Targets, Network Targets, and Access 
Specifications tabs show current settings for that worker; any changes are 
applied to that worker.
</para><para>
If you click on a manager, targets selected in the Disk Targets or 
Network Targets tab are distributed in a round-robin fashion among the 
manager's disk or network workers (as appropriate). The other controls in 
the Disk Targets, Network Targets, and Access Specifications tabs display 
the common settings of all the manager's workers of the appropriate 
type (a value is shown if all workers have the same value, or the control 
is blank if not all workers have the same value). Any changes you make are 
applied to all the manager's workers of the appropriate type.
</para><para>
If you click on All Managers, no targets are shown in the Disk Targets or 
Network Targets tab, because managers target lists may be different.  
The other controls in the Disk Targets, Network Targets, and Access 
Specifications tabs display the common settings of all workers of the 
appropriate type; any changes you make are applied to all workers of the 
appropriate type.
</para><para>
Double-click on a manager or All Managers to hide or display its children
</para><para>
By draging a worker, manager, or All Managers to a bar chart in 
the Results Display tab, you are able to see its results as the test is 
running.
</para><para>
To add a manager on the same machine as Iometer, press the 
Start New Manager button on the toolbar.
</para><para>
To add a manager on another machine, start Dynamo on the desired machine, 
providing the name of the machine running Iometer as a command-line 
argument (as described under *****Running Iometer above); additional 
managers can be started before or after Iometer. 
</para><para>
To remove a manager, click on the manager and press the Disconnect button 
on the toolbar; this terminates the specified Dynamo process.
</para><para>
To remove all managers, click on <emphasis>All Managers</emphasis> and 
press the Disconnect button on the toolbar.
</para><para>
By default, each manager starts off with one disk worker for each 
processor on the manager's machine. To add a worker to a manager, click 
on the manager or any of its workers and press the Start Disk Worker or 
Start Network Worker button on the toolbar. 
</para><para>
To remove a worker, click on the worker and press the Disconnect 
button on the toolbar.
</para><para>
By default, each manager has the same name as the machine on which it is 
running, and each worker has the name <emphasis>Worker n.</emphasis> You 
can change the name of a manager or worker by clicking on the name when 
the manager or worker is selected (you will have to wait a moment for the 
name to highlight). The name of <emphasis>All Managers</emphasis> cannot 
be changed.
</para><para>
At most one list item (manager, worker, or All Managers) can be 
selected at a time.
</para><para>
The settings for the selected worker or the selected manager's or 
managers' workers are shown in the Disk Targets, Network Targets, and 
Access Specifications tabs.
</para><para>
Right-clicking on a manager pops up a menu with one item: 
<emphasis>Refresh Target Lists.</emphasis>
</para><para>
Selecting this item causes the manager to update its lists of disks and 
network interfaces. You can use this to update Iometer's view of the 
manager if the target status for a manager changes (for example, if you 
create an iobw.tst file or mount a logical disk).
</para>
</sect2>
