<sect1 id="quickstart">
<title>Quick Start</title>
<para>
This section is a rapid introduction to Iometer that will help you get up 
and running fast.
</para>
<sect2 id="disk">
<title>Testing Disk Performance</title>
<para>
To test disk performance:
</para>
<orderedlist>
<listitem><para>
Double-click on Iometer.exe. The Iometer main window appears, and a  
Dynamo workload generator is automatically launched on the local computer.
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Click on a manager (the name of the local computer) in the Topology panel 
on the left side of the Iometer window. The manager's available disk 
drives appear in the Disk Targets tab. Blue icons represent physical 
drives; they are only shown if they have no partitions on them. Yellow 
icons represent logical (mounted) drives; they are only shown if they are 
writable. A yellow icon with a red slash through it means that the drive 
needs to be prepared before the test starts; see the Disk Targets Tab  
Reference section for more information on preparation.
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
In the Disk Targets tab, select a disk or disks to use in the test (use 
Shift-click and Control-click to select multiple disks). The selected 
disks will be automatically distributed among the manager's workers (threads). 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Switch to the Access Specifications tab. Double-click on 'Default' in the 
Global Access Specifications list (the one with the globe icon). The Edit 
Access Specification dialog appears. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
The Edit Access Specification dialog shows you how the disk will be 
accessed. The default is 2-Kilobyte random I/Os with a mix of 67% reads 
and 33% writes, which represents a typical database workload. You can 
leave it alone or change it. Press OK to close the dialog when you are 
through. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
For maximum throughput (Megabytes per second), try changing the Transfer  
Request Size to 64K, the Percent Read/Write Distribution to 100% Read, 
and the Percent Random/Sequential Distribution to 100% Sequential.
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
For the maximum I/O rate (I/O operations per second), try changing the  
Transfer Request Size to 512 bytes, the Percent Read/Write Distribution 
to 100% Read, and the Percent Random/Sequential Distribution to 100% 
Sequential. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Switch to the Results Display tab. Set the Update Frequency to 10 seconds. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Press the Start Tests button (green flag). A standard Save File dialog 
appears. Select a file to store the test results (default results.csv). 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
After 10 seconds the first test results appear in the Results Display 
tab, and they are updated every 10 seconds after that. Press the button 
to the left of each bar chart for a menu of the different results you can 
display. You can also drag a worker or manager from the Topology panel to 
a bar chart to see the results of just that worker or manager. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Press the Stop Test button (stop sign). The test stops and the final 
results are saved in the results.csv file. This is a comma-separated text 
file that can be viewed in any text editor or imported into a 
spreadsheet. 
</para></listitem>
</orderedlist>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="network">
<title>Testing Network Performance</title>
<para>
To test network performance between two computers (A and B): 
</para>
<orderedlist>
<listitem><para>
On computer A, double-click on Iometer.exe. The Iometer main window  
appears and a Dynamo workload generator is automatically launched on 
computer A. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
On computer B, open an MS-DOS Command Prompt window and execute Dynamo, 
specifying computer A's name as a command line argument. For example: 
<screen>C:\> dynamo /i computer_a /m computer_b</screen>
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
On computer A again, note that computer B has appeared as a new manager 
in the Topology panel. Click on it and note that its disk drives appear 
in the Disk Targets tab. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
With computer B selected in the Topology panel, press the Start Network 
Worker button (picture of network cables). This creates a network server 
on computer B. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
With computer B still selected in the Topology panel, switch to the 
Network Targets tab, which shows the two computers and their network 
interfaces. Select one of computer A's network interfaces from the list. 
This creates a network client on computer A and connects the client and 
server together. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Switch to the Access Specifications tab. Double-click on 'Default' in the 
Global Access Specifications list. In the Edit Access Specification 
dialog, specify a Transfer Request Size of 512 bytes. Press OK to close 
the dialog. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Switch to the Results Display tab. Set the Update Frequency to 10 
seconds. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Press the Start Tests button. Select a file to store the test results. If 
you specify an existing file, the new results will be appended to the 
existing ones. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Watch the results in the Results Display tab.
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Press the Stop Test button to stop the test and save the results.
</para></listitem>
</orderedlist>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="importaccess">
<title>Importing Results into Microsoft Access</title>
<para>
To import a results.csv file into a Microsoft Access database using the 
Import Wizard:
</para>
<orderedlist>
<listitem><para>
Double-click on Wizard.mdb to open Access. (If you use Access 2000, you 
will be notified that the database is not in Access 2000 format. It does 
not have to be in order to perform the import.) The first page of the 
wizard appears.
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Specify the results file to import. Use the Browse button to locate it if 
it isn't in the same directory as the Wizard.mdb file. Press Next. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Select the test(s) from the file that you want to import. Press Next. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Select 'Create a new database.' Press Next. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Specify the new .mdb file to import into. This must be a different file 
from Wizard.mdb. Press Next. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Review your settings and press Finish. The results are imported into the 
specified database. 
</para></listitem>
</orderedlist>
</sect2>
<sect2 id="graphexcel">
<title>Graphing Results in Microsoft Excel</title>
<para>
To graph imported results into a Microsoft Excel spreadsheet using the 
Graph Wizard: 
</para>
<orderedlist>
<listitem><para>
Open Wizard.mdb in Access, if necessary. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Click the Graph Data button. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Specify the database file that contains your imported data. This must be 
a database produced by the Import Wizard. Press Next. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Select the test(s) from the database that you want to graph. Press Next. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
This list shows predefined graph types that you can use. Press New to 
define a new graph type. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Select the '# Disks' database field to graph on the X axis. Press Next. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Type a name to label the X axis, or accept the field name as the default. 
Press Next. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Check 'Allow multiple Y values.' Select the 'IOps' and 'MBps' database 
fields to graph on the Y axis. Press Next.
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Click on the MBps field and press 'Edit selected label.' Click 'Right 
axis' to graph this field on the right axis of the graph. Change the name 
to be displayed on the Y axis label if you like. Press OK, then Next. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
The grouping criterion can be used to group the data into several 
distinct lines on the graph. For now, leave 'None' selected. Press Next. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Leave the grouping criterion label blank. Press Next. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Type a name for the graph type you have just defined, or accept the 
default. Press Next. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
You have now defined a new graph type that you can edit or re-use in the 
future. Select it from the list (if it isn't already selected). Press 
Next. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Specify an .xls file to receive the graph. This can be a new or existing 
file; if the file exists, the graph will be added to it. Press Next. 
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
Review your settings and press Finish. The graph is created in the 
specified spreadsheet. (If you just imported the results from one or two 
tests, it is probably a very boring graph with only one or two points! 
The Graph Wizard is most useful in graphing the results of multiple tests 
against each other.)
</para></listitem>
</orderedlist>
</sect2>
</sect1>
