<sect3 id="targets">
<title>Targets</title>

<mediaobject>
<imageobject role="html">
<imagedata fileref="images/targets.jpg" format="JPG" align="left"/>
</imageobject>
<imageobject role="fo">
<imagedata fileref="images/targets.jpg" format="JPG" align="left"/>
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>

<para>
The Targets list displays the disk drives available to the worker or 
manager selected in the Topology panel. Disks that are selected (checked) 
in the Targets list will be used by the worker(s) during the test.
</para><para>
Yellow disk icons represent logical drives (i.e. those with a drive 
letter). They are shown only if they are writeable. Disk workers access 
logical drives by reading and writing to the file 
<emphasis>iobw.tst</emphasis> in the root directory of the drive. If this 
file exists, the drive is shown with a plain yellow icon. If the file 
doesn't exist, the icon has a red slash through it.
</para><para>
If you select a drive that does not have an iobw.tst file, Iometer will 
begin the test by creating this file and expanding it until the drive is 
full (this is shown as .Preparing Drives. in the status bar). You can 
change the size of this file to control how much of the disk Iometer can 
use by setting the Maximum Disk Size control to the desired size (in 
sectors).
</para><para>
Blue disk icons represent physical drives. They are shown only if they 
contain nothing but free space (no defined partitions). Disk workers 
access physical drives by writing direct to the raw disk. Physical drives 
do not use an iobw.tst file. Running with physical drives is recommended.
</para><para>
You can select any number of drives; by default, no drives are selected. 
Click on a single drive to select it; Shift-click to select a range of 
drives; Control-click to add a drive to or remove a drive from the current 
selection. You can also use the arrow keys, Home and End keys, and the 
space bar to move the highlight and  select/deselect disks, or press 
<emphasis>Control-A</emphasis> to select all drives (this requires the 
keyboard focus to be in the Disk Targets tab).
</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>
If a disk worker is selected in the Topology panel, the Targets list  
displays the disks available to that worker. Drives that you select in the 
Targets list are used by that worker during the test.
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
If a manager is selected in the Topology panel, the Targets list displays 
the disks available to that manager. Drives that you select in the Targets 
list are used by that manager's disk workers during the test. (Network 
workers are not affected.) The selected drives are distributed in a 
round-robin fashion among the manager's disk workers; any previous drive 
assignments for those workers are replaced by the new assignment.
</para><para>
For example, suppose the selected manager has four disk workers and
you select seven drives. In this case, drives 1 and 5 will be used by 
Worker 1; drives 2 and 6 will be used by Worker 2, drives 3 and 7 will be 
used by Worker 3, and drive 4 will be used by Worker 4.
</para><para>
Note that if you click on a manager, the selected disks for that manager's 
workers are shown only if the drives are distributed among the workers in 
a round-robin fashion. If this is not the case, all the check boxes are 
gray, and you must click on an individual worker to see its selected 
disks.
</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>
If <emphasis>All Managers</emphasis> is selected in the Topology panel, 
the Targets list is disabled.
</para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</sect3>

<sect3 id="disksize">
<title>Maximum Disk Size</title>

<mediaobject>
<imageobject role="html">
<imagedata fileref="images/maxdisk.jpg" format="JPG" align="left"/>
</imageobject>
<imageobject role="fo">
<imagedata fileref="images/maxdisk.jpg" format="JPG" align="left"/>
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>

<para>
The Maximum Disk Size control specifies how many disk sectors are used by 
the selected worker(s). The default is 0, meaning the entire disk or  
\iobw.tst file (beginning with the Starting Disk Sector). If you specify a 
value other than zero, Iometer uses the specified number of 512-byte disk 
sectors, beginning with the Starting Disk Sector. If the specified value 
would extend beyond the end of the disk or file, it is silently ignored, 
and the default of 0 is used.
</para><para>
For example, if Starting Disk Sector is 5 and Maximum Disk Size is 10, 
the selected worker(s) will use sectors 5-14 of the disk or \iobw.tst 
file.
</para><para>
When preparing an unprepared logical drive (that is, the iobw.tst file 
does not exist), Iometer uses the sum of the values of the Maximum Disk 
Size + Starting Disk Sector controls as an upper bound on the size of 
iobw.tst. The iobw.tst file is created with this size (or available space, 
if smaller). If the file already exists (the drive has already been 
prepared), changing this control will not resize iobw.tst.
</para>
<note><title>Note</title>
<para>
When two or more workers are assigned to the same unprepared logical
drive, the Maximum Disk Size + Starting Disk Sector of the first worker
determines the size of iobw.tst.
</para></note>

</sect3>

<sect3 id="start">
<title>Starting Disk Sector</title>

<mediaobject>
<imageobject role="html">
<imagedata fileref="images/startdisk.jpg" format="JPG" align="left"/>
</imageobject>
<imageobject role="fo">
<imagedata fileref="images/startdisk.jpg" format="JPG" align="left"/>
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>

<para>
The Starting Disk Sector control specifies the lowest-numbered disk 
sector used by the selected worker(s) during the test. The default is 0, 
meaning the first 512-byte sector in the disk or \iobw.tst file.
</para>
</sect3>

<sect3 id="numio">
<title># of Outstanding I/Os</title>

<mediaobject>
<imageobject role="html">
<imagedata fileref="images/numio.jpg" format="JPG" align="left"/>
</imageobject>
<imageobject role="fo">
<imagedata fileref="images/numio.jpg" format="JPG" align="left"/>
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>

<para>
The # of Outstanding I/Os control specifies the maximum number of 
outstanding asynchronous I/O operations per disk the selected worker(s) 
will attempt to have active at one time. (The actual queue depth seen by 
the disks may be less if the operations complete very quickly.) The 
default value is 1.
</para><para>
Note that the value of this control applies to each selected worker and 
each selected disk. For example, suppose you select a manager with 4 disk 
workers in the Topology panel, select 8 disks in the Disk Targets tab, and 
specify a # of Outstanding I/Os of 16. In this case, the disks will be 
distributed among the workers (2 disks per worker), and each worker will 
generate a maximum of 16 outstanding I/Os to each of its disks. The system 
as a whole will have a maximum of 128 outstanding I/Os at a time (4 
workers * 2 disks/worker * 16 outstanding I/Os per disk) from this manager.
</para><para>
This control can be overridden by the # of Outstanding I/Os control group 
in the Test Setup tab (depending on the Cycling Options).
</para>
<note><title>Note</title>
<para>
If the total number of outstanding I/Os in the system is very large, 
Iometer or Windows may hang, thrash, or crash. The exact value of 
<emphasis>very large</emphasis> depends on the disk driver and the amount 
of physical memory available. This problem is due to limitations in 
Windows and some disk drivers, and is not a problem with the Iometer 
software. The problem is seen in Iometer and not in other applications 
because Iometer makes it easy to specify a number of outstanding I/Os that 
is much larger than typical applications produce.
</para></note>
</sect3>

<sect3 id="testrate">
<title>Test Connection Rate</title>

<mediaobject>
<imageobject role="html">
<imagedata fileref="images/testcon.jpg" format="JPG" align="left"/>
</imageobject>
<imageobject role="fo">
<imagedata fileref="images/testcon.jpg" format="JPG" align="left"/>
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>

<para>
The Test Connection Rate control specifies how often the worker(s) open 
and close their disk(s). The default is off, meaning that all the disks 
are opened at the beginning of the test and are not closed until the end 
of the test. If you turn this control on, you can specify a number of 
transactions to perform between opening and closing. (A transaction is an 
I/O request and the corresponding reply, if any; see the Reply field in
the Edit Access Specification dialog for more information).
</para><para>
If Test Connection Rate is on, the worker opens all its disks at the 
beginning of the test. When the specified number of transactions has been 
performed to a particular disk, that disk is closed, and is re-opened 
again just before the next I/O to the disk. The number of transactions can 
be zero, in which case the worker just opens and closes the disks 
repeatedly.
</para><para>
Each open + transactions + close sequence is called a connection. The 
time from the initiation of the open to the completion of the 
corresponding close is recorded for each connection, and the maximum and 
average connection time and the average connections per second are 
reported.
</para>
</sect3>
